Hello moneywise friends.  Welcome back to
another episode of the Moneywise
Engineer.  In today's video, let's talk about
two popular global
multi-asset income funds that provide
monthly dividends.  The ALFM Global
Multi-asset Income Fund and the Manulife
Global Multi-asset Income Feeder Fund.
Many people ask what the difference is between
these two funds and which is
better to invest in.
Both Manu Life and ALFM are considered
investment funds.  Investment fund is the
general term.  The money
of many investors is pooled together, which is why
they are called pulled funds.  Then there is a fund
manager who manages the funds and
decides where to allocate the money.
Is it in stocks, bonds or other securities
to grow the investment?  But of course
there is an annual management fee.  This is the
fee for the fund manager's work.
The fund manager will research,
monitor, and manage the fund
for you.  The good thing about investment
funds is that even if you're not an expert, you can
invest in a diversified portfolio of
assets and you don't need a lot of
capital to get started.  Usually
the minimum investment is Php1,000 for
global funds and below Php1,000
for local funds.  So if you want to
invest but don't want the hassle of
choosing individual stocks and don't have
time to do research, investment funds
might be a good option for you.  There
are two types of investment funds, UITFs
and mutual funds.  ITFs are regulated by
the BSP and these are offered by banks
or trust companies.  Mutual funds
are regulated by the SEC and these
are offered by asset management
companies or mutual fund companies.
NAVPU stands for net asset value per
unit.  This is the price per unit of an
investment fund.  It's like the share price of
mutual funds or UITFs.  So if
the NAV increases over time, the
value of your investment will also increase.  But if it
goes down, there is a chance you will lose money if
you sell it at a lower price.
There are two ways to earn from dividend
funds.  First of all, from dividend payouts.
This is the regular cash distributions
coming from the earnings of the fund.
You can reinvest it to grow
your investment even more.  You can also
withdraw if you need extra
cash.  And second is through capital
appreciation.  Aside from dividends, there is the
potential for the fund's value to increase
over time.  So you earn when you sell
your units at a higher price than when
you bought them.  If there are dividend
funds, there are also growth funds.  In
growth funds, there are no dividends.  It does not
provide regular cash payouts.
You only earn from growth funds through
capital appreciation.  When the
value of your fund increases, you can sell it
to make a profit.  from the price
difference.  Dividend or income funds,
on the other hand, regularly distribute
dividends to investors.  So
this is a good option if your goal is consistent
cash flow.  You make money even if you don't
sell your fund units.  But take
note, the potential returns may be lower
compared to growth funds.  Because
the focus of dividend funds is income
payout, not capital appreciation.
Let's start with ALFM Global Multiasset
income Fund.  This is the most popular
dividend paying fund because
this fund is accessible even if you don't have an account
with a broker.  It is available at Ginvest
Gfunds and is also available at Maya Investa
Funds.  This fund is suitable for
investors with an aggressive risk profile.
The ALFM Global Multi-asset Income Fund
is a multi-asset feeder fund.  Under the
mutual fund category, it invests at
least 90% of its assets in a target fund
which is the Black Rock Global Fund.
It is managed by Black Rock, one of the
largest asset management companies
in the world.  In terms of asset
allocation, 49.74% 74%
are invested in fixed income such as
bonds and similar instruments that
provide stability and steady income.
40.12%
is in equities for long-term
growth potential and the remaining
10.14%
is in cash and cash equivalents that are
used as a buffer or ready to
invest capital.  The allocation to
North America is large at 70.83%,
mostly US-based companies, followed
by Europe, and there is also some exposure
to emerging markets Asia Pacific and
Japan.  Volatility measures how
much the fund price moves over
time.  In this case, the
volatility of this fund is only moderate.  It's not too
aggressive but not too
conservative either.  Take note, since this is a
balanced fund, the main focus is regular
dividend income, not capital
appreciation.  So don't expect
the navpu to increase quickly.
His strength is monthly cash flow through
consistent dividend payouts.  So if
your goal is diversified global
exposure plus passive income, this fund
might be suitable for you.  These are the
top 10 holdings.  It's a mix of ETFs,
bonds, and global blue chip companies.
There is exposure to high dividend USETFs,
short duration corporate bonds and top
technology names like Microsoft, Apple,
Nvidia and Meta.  The fund is well
diversified across different asset
classes and sectors offering a balance
between income stability and long-term
growth potential.
So main portfolio changes as of April
2025. They decreased the exposure to
long-term US bonds due to less interest
from foreign buyers.  And then they added
Japanese yen exposure as a hedge for the
portfolio.  Rotated some equity exposure
from US to Europe and UK stocks and they
added more dividend paying stocks and US
high yield fixed income investments that
could boost returns.  Due to US tariff
announcements, stock and bond markets
became very volatile in April.  And
looking ahead managers expect continued
uncertainty in global markets.  But they
believe this is the perfect time for a
multi-asset strategy that focuses on
high quality income generating
investments that are flexible and can adjust to
different market conditions.
This is the performance of the ALFM Global
Multiasset Income Fund.  So the fund
started to gain momentum in late 2023
and uptrend until 2024. But the
fund was affected by the tariff
announcement from Trump in April 2025,
which is why the price also fell.  Here's the
dividend yield history of ALFM from
March 2024 to April 2025. The annualized
dividend yield ranges from 5.66%
to 6.17%.
The average yield is at 5.93%.
And then from January 2025 the yield went up to 6%
.  So hopefully
the dividend yield will continue to be above 6%.  Take note,
this is the net dividend yield.
The management fee will not be deducted here.
It also does not deduct from your number of fund
units, which is a common
misconception among others who invest in
this fund.  They thought the
management fee would be reduced here and it would also be reduced from the
number of funds.  That's wrong.  The
dividends paid are derived from the fund's earnings
and distributed separately as cash
dividends.
Record date is usually at the end of the
month around the 28th of the month.  So
you must have held fund units before the
record date so that you are qualified for
dividends in the following months.  Payment
date usually around 15th to 19th day of
the month.  So this is where you will receive the
cash dividend in your account.  Here's the
cumulative performance of ALFM Global
Multi-asset Income Fund.  So let's look at
the peso class.
This fund's short-term performance is somewhat weak,
but its long-term returns are still positive
.  The 3-year cumulative return of the
Peso Class is 12.13%
and 10.46%
since inception.  Take note, returns are
already net of fees.  Meaning,
this includes the annual management fee and
other charges.  There is no longer a separate payment
for management fees because many people
are asking when
the management fees will be deducted.  You won't
feel it anymore because
he has already been incorporated into the NAVP.  Since this is a balanced
fund, we don't expect
the returns to be very high.  This is not like
pure equity funds which have higher growth
potential like growth funds.  The
primary goal of this fund is to
provide monthly income through dividends
with the potential for capital growth
over the long term.  Minimum investment
is Php1,000
and the minimum additional
investment is lower.  It's only Php100 at the broker and
pesos, so you can use GCash.  And there is a
holding period of 180 days and an early
redemption fee of 1% if you redeem
in less than 180 days.  The annual management
fee is 1.5%
but it is already incorporated into the NAVP.  So
it will not be deducted separately.  By
order process time is t+ 1 day.  The
cutoff time is 2 p.m.  Sell ​​order
processing is T+ 5 days.  The
buy and sell processing time is longer at Ginvest.
Buy orders take up to 4 business days and
sell orders take up to 8 business days
.  Now, let's talk about the
Manu Life Global Multi-asset Diversified
income feeder fund.  It was also launched in 2021
.  So they are the same age as
ALFM.  This fund is suitable for
investors with an aggressive risk profile.
This fund is under the UITF
category.  His target fund is Manu
Life Global Fund.  This is the
portfolio composition.  100% invested
in target fund.  The fund aims to balance
income and growth by investing in a mix
of bonds both high yield and investment
grade and also has equities.
There's a slightly higher allocation to
bonds total of 44.35%
to generate income while the total
equities at 42.07%
provide potential for growth.  Others
could include reads, preferred shares or
other alternative assets.  That's it.  So these are the
top holdings.  It includes a
combination of government debt
instruments, blue chip technology stocks
and corporate bonds which help reduce
risk through diversification.
Looking ahead, market volatility is
expected to continue.  There are still
downside risks to the economy, especially
with tighter credit conditions.  That's
why the fund manager will continue using
tactical positioning, meaning they will
actively adjust the portfolio to manage
risk while also taking advantage of new
yield opportunities as they come.  This
chart shows the navpu performance of the
fund, the green line compared to the
benchmark, the blue line.  Despite the
market fluctuations
which are part of market cycles, the
fund shows long-term upward growth
overall.  Same as ALFM, short-term returns
were negative but the fund still managed
to deliver positive long-term gains.
3year change is 22.51% 51%
and 31.18%
since Inception in 2021. However,
compared to the benchmark,
it has underperformed somewhat.  Returns are
already net of fees.  So there is no separate
payment for management fees.  This is
the annualized dividend yield history of the
Manual Fund from April 2024 to April
2025. So the annual yield
ranges from 6.12%
to 6.96%.
The average yield is around 6.47%.
He is higher versus ALFM global
multi-asset income fund.  The dividend
yield is generally increasing from 6.12%
in April 2024 to 6.96%
in April 2025. Although there is fluctuation,
overall its dividend is increasing.
This is also a net dividend yield.  There are no fees
or taxes to be deducted here.  Minimum
investment and additional investment is
Php1,000.
This fund has no holding period, so there is
no early redemption fee.  The
annual trust fee is 1.75%
but it is already incorporated into the NAVBU.
Here's the overall summary for the fund
comparison and the winner is Manuif
Global Multiasset diversified income
feeder fund.  So this is now
my favorite dividend paying fund.
Manual life fund is available at
Dragonfy Securities.  Both funds are
available at First Metrosec.  Almost
all funds are available at
First Metrosec.  How about you?  Which of
these two fans is your favorite?
Let me know in the comments below.
Also follow my Facebook
page, The Money Wise Engineer for more
updates.